### WESLEY BILL

Fort Bragg, NC · 253-343-3273 · HYPERLINK

"mailto:wesbill12@gmail.com" wesbill12@gmail.com · HYPERLINK "https://www.linkedin.com/in/wesley-bill-3602191a3/" LinkedIn Profile

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

### **Information Technology Security Analyst**

Highly trained professional capable of designing and enforcing policies and procedures that protect an organization's computing infrastructure from all forms of security breaches.

Able to take charge identifying vulnerabilities and working with IT colleagues to aptly resolve them, ensuring that the network and data reliably remains secure.

Expert analytical skills and an in-depth knowledge of best practices underscores ability to adeptly prevent a wide range of security threats and to expertly train and educate staff in various information security topics.

Active Top Secret / Sensitive Compartmented Information (TS/SCI) security clearance.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

United States Army - USA / Afghanistan

**2011 - PRESENT** 

#### **Staff Sergeant**

# **Operations Manager** - Fort Bragg, NC **2018** - **Present**

Earned merit promotions, moving up from squad leader to assistant operations and now chief operations manager, coordinating battalion activities and allocating the resources for plans and operations.

Supervised operations in support of airborne corps, managing personnel utilization and resources in support of training and operations for 400 personnel, and responsible for \$200,000+ of equipment.

Served in the Security Force Assistance Brigade (SFAB), a specialized unit of highly trained soldiers and among the top Army tactical leaders.

Praised by leadership, "Displayed exceptional leadership capabilities...dedication to leadership, training and unit administration epitomizes the ideals of the NCO corps.

## Platoon Sergeant / Section Leader - Fort Bragg, NC 2016 - 2018

Promoted from 12-man section unit leader to take charge of 18-man platoon; responsible for their health, welfare, discipline, morale, and esprit de corps, and for the maintenance and accountability of \$5+ million worth of equipment.

Noted by superior, "...is in the top 10% of Staff Sergeants that I have worked with over my 14-year career."

Lauded for displaying a "genuine care and concern for paratroopers and their families; was eager to reinforce personal and professional growth of subordinates."

# **Squad Leader -** Fort Bragg, NC **2015 - 2016**

Led 9-man squad taking charge for the health, welfare, discipline, morale, and training of the unit.

Recognized by leadership for standing out among peers and "is constantly recognized by unit leadership for his efforts; his tactical proficiency and leadership abilities directly contributed to the

overwhelming success of the unit's mission."

#### **Awards & Decorations** - partial listing

Army Achievement Medal 4x Army Good Conduct Medal 2x National Defense Service Medal Afghanistan Campaign Medal Global War on Terrorism Service Medal NCO Professional Development Ribbon NATO Medal Army Combat Infantryman Badge Pathfinder Badge Senior Parachute Badge

#### **EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS**

CompTIA A+ Certified 2020

CompTIA Security+ Certified 2020

CompTIA Network+ Certified

Process/Expected JUL2020

Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)

In Process/Expected 2021

**Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH)** 

In Process/Expected 2021

Harding High School - Marion, OH

2010

**Diploma Conferred** 

In